venturebeatprofiles.com 2010-11-30

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

Last Updated: January 31, 2008

Your privacy is our top concern. We work hard to earn and keep your trust, so we adhere to the following principles to protect your privacy:

  * We will not rent or sell your personally identifiable information to third parties for marketing purposes.
  * We will not share your contact information with another user, without your consent. 
  * Any sensitive information that you provide will be secured with industry standard protocols and technology. 

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

VentureBeat, Inc. (the "Company") reserves the right to revise this Privacy Policy at any time. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account.

Notice of all changes that materially affect ways in which your personally identifiable data may be used or shared will be posted in updates to our Privacy Policy. If you continue to use the VentureBeat Profiles service after notice of changes have been sent to you or published on our site, you hereby provide your consent to the changed practices.

Please read this privacy policy to learn more about:

  1. What personally identifiable information of yours is collected by the Company. 
  2. How the information is used. 
  3. With whom the information may be shared. 
  4. How you can access and change your Account information.
  5. What security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information collected by the Company.
  6. How to contact us.

#### Information Collection

##### Registration:

In order to become a VentureBeat Profiles user, you must first create an account on this web site. To create an account you are required to provide the following contact information: name, email address, country, ZIP/postal code, and choose a user ID and a password.

##### Profile Information:

Once a user, you may provide additional information in the Profile section describing your background, work experience, and relationship to companies in our database. You may also upload a profile picture. Providing additional information beyond what is required at registration is entirely optional, but enables you to find new opportunities in the VentureBeat Profiles system.

##### Information about Your Contacts:

In order to invite others to connect with you directly in VentureBeat Profiles, you will enter their names and email addresses. This information will be used by VentureBeat Profiles to send your invitation including a message that you write. The names and email addresses of people that you invite will be used only to send your invitation and reminders.

You may also choose to manually enter or upload data about your contacts into the private "My Friends" section of our website. All information entered there will only be viewable by you and will not be searchable by others in the VentureBeat Profiles network without your permission.

All information that you enter or upload about your contacts will be covered by the same terms of this privacy policy as cover your own personally identifiable information.

##### Information for Contests and Sweepstakes:

If we offer a contest or sweepstakes, we may ask for additional information such as name, address, and phone number in order to provide the winner with their prize. We would not use that information for any other purpose unless we receive consent at the time you provide the information.

##### Our Newsletters & Alerts:

If you sign up to receive our newsletter or email alerts, we will use your email address to send you newsletters or email alerts.

##### Cookies & Log Files:

Like most web sites, VentureBeat Profiles uses cookies and web log files to track site usage. A cookie is a tiny data file which resides on your computer which allows VentureBeat Profiles to recognize you as a user when you return to our site using the same computer and web browser. Unfortunately, if your browser settings do not allow cookies, you will not be able to use our website. Like the information you enter at registration or in your Profile, cookie and log file data is used to customize your experience on the web site.

One type of cookie, known as a "persistent" cookie, is set once you've logged in to your VentureBeat Profiles account. The next time you visit the VentureBeat Profiles web site, the persistent cookie will allow us to recognize you as an existing user so you will not need to log in before using the service. In order to access or change any of your private information (like a credit card number), however, you must log in securely again with your password even if your computer contains your persistent cookie. Additionally, if you log out of the VentureBeat Profiles site you will need to re-enter your password the next time you visit in order to log in to your account. Another type of cookie, called a "session" cookie, is used to identify a particular visit to the VentureBeat Profiles site. Session cookies expire after a short time or when you close your web browser.

Due to the communications standards on the Internet, when you visit the VentureBeat Profiles web site we automatically receive the URL of the site from which you came and the site to which you are going when you leave VentureBeat Profiles. We also receive the Internet protocol (IP) address of your computer (or the proxy server you use to access the World Wide Web), your computer operating system and type of web browser you are using, as well as the name of your ISP. This information is used to analyze overall trends to help us improve the VentureBeat Profiles service. The linkage between your IP address and your personally identifiable information is not shared with third-parties without your permission or except when required by law.

##### Children:

You must be 18 years or older to be eligible to use this site and the VentureBeat Profiles service. If you are not yet 18 years old, please do not submit to us any personal information and discontinue using this site immediately.

#### Information Use

VentureBeat Profiles is an online service dedicated to helping all users more effectively share and discuss company information and connect with one another. The personally identifiable information you choose to provide on this site is used to help identify and describe you to other users and help facilitate communications between you and other users. Other information, that does not personally identify you as an individual, is collected by the Company from the site (such as, by way of example, patterns of utilization) and is exclusively owned by the Company. This information can be utilized by the Company in such manner as the Company, in its sole discretion, deems appropriate.

##### VentureBeat Profiles Communications:

The Company will communicate with you through email and notices posted on this web site. These include a series of welcome emails which help inform new users about various features of the service. Please be aware that you will always receive certain emails from the Company related to the proper functioning of your account, such as email notices when another user in your network tries to contact you. The Company may send you promotional information unless you have opted out of receiving such information. If you wish to opt-out of receiving promotional emails, please send a request to [help@venturebeat.com](mailto:help@venturebeat.com).

##### Customized Content:

Information you provide at registration or in your Profile section is also used to customize your experience on the web site. For example, when you login to your account we will display the screen names of new users who have recently joined your network.

##### Investigating Potential Abuse:

We may use any information provided to us by a user, including personally identifiable information, along with any data gathered from our web logs and from third parties to conduct investigations, and we may disclose this information to third parties, including law enforcement officials, investigators, or private parties seeking to protect and enforce their rights; if

  * we have a good faith belief that it is necessary to comply with a court order, judicial proceeding, legal process, subpoena or warrant; 
  * we have a good faith belief that it is necessary to enforce the terms and conditions of the Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy, exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims; or 
  * we believe that your actions violate the law or our Terms of Use or threaten the rights, property, or safety of the Company, the web site, our users, the companies in our database, or others.

#### Identification of a Contributor

When you edit and publish a information on VentureBeat Profiles, we keep track of who contributed to our site. You will be identified by your user name. This may be your real name if you so choose, or you may choose to publish under a pseudonym, which is the user name you selected when you registered for the VentureBeat Profiles service.

#### Information Sharing

##### Sharing Information with Third Parties:

The Company takes the privacy of our users very seriously. We will not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personally identifiable information to any third parties for marketing purposes. We will only share your personally identifiable information with third parties to carry out your instructions and to provide specific services. For example, we may use a credit card processing company to bill users for subscription fees. These third parties do not retain, share, or store any personally identifiable information except to provide these services and are bound by strict confidentiality agreements which limit their use of such information.

We may provide aggregated data about the usage of our services to third-parties for such purposes as we deem, in our sole discretion, to be appropriate. We may segment our users by role (i.e. product managers, vice presidents), industry, geographic location, company. If you would like to be excluded from the aggregated research or products based upon aggregated data about our users' activities on the site, please email customer service at [help@venturebeat.com](mailto:help@venturebeat.com).

##### Partnering with Other Organizations to Offer Combined Services:

The Company may partner with other online services to give you the combined results of those services. For example we may partner with a job search site to let you use their services to find jobs and then to use VentureBeat Profiles to find trusted referrals to those jobs. Whenever we offer such combined services it will be your choice to make use of the combined services or not. In these cases, your personally identifiable information will only be passed from VentureBeat Profiles to the partner if you choose to use the combined service.

##### Communications Between Users:

Many emails you initiate through VentureBeat Profiles, such as an invitation sent to a non-user, will list your email address and name in the header of the message. Emails you initiate may also provide aggregate information about your network (for instance how many people are in your network), but will not list the people to whom you're directly connected. Other communications that you initiate through the VentureBeat Profiles website, like a request for contact, will list your name as the initiator but will not include your personal contact information. Your contact information will only be shared with another user if both of you have indicated that you would like to establish contact with each other.

##### Your Posts:

It goes without saying that any personally identifiable information that you submit on any blog, discussion thread or other publicly accesible area on the web site can be read, collected, or used by other user of the site and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit to the publicly accessible area of the Site.

#### Transfer of Information

We may syndicate the information you posted about companies to third parties. Your first name and last initial and any personally identifiable information you have included in your posts may be transferred to such third parties and displayed on their websites in connection with such third parties' publication of your posts. 

We reserve the right to transfer your personal information in the event of a transfer of ownership of the Company, such as an acquisition by or merger with another company. In addition, we may sell or transfer assets or portions of our business as we continue to improve our product and service offerings. In such transactions, user or visitor information (whether personally identifiable or not) may constitute one of the transferred business assets. In any such event, the Company will notify you before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. 

We will notify you when information about you may be provided to third parties in ways other than explained above, and you will have the option to prevent such information sharing. 

#### Links

VentureBeat Profiles may contain links to other web sites. The Company is not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites. When linking to another web site, you should read the privacy policy state on that web site. Our privacy policy only governs information collected on VentureBeat Profiles.

#### Third Party Advertising

Ads appearing on this site may be delivered to users by the Company or one of our advertising partners. Our web advertising partners may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by VentureBeat Profiles only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

#### Accessing and Changing Your Account Information

You can review the personal information you provided us and make any desired changes to the information, or to the settings for your VentureBeat Profiles account, at any time by logging in to your account on the VentureBeat Profiles web site and editing the information on your Profile page. You can also close your account by sending a request to [help@venturebeat.com](mailto:help@venturebeat.com). If you close your VentureBeat Profiles account, we will remove your name and other personally identifiable information from our publicly viewable data. We may retain certain data contributed by you if it may be necessary to prevent fraud or future abuse, or for legitimate business purposes, such as analysis of aggregated, non-personally-identifiable data, account recovery, or if required by law. All retained data will continue to be subject to the terms of the VentureBeat Profiles Privacy Policy that you have previously agreed to. 

#### Security

In order to secure your personal information, access to your data on VentureBeat Profiles is password-protected, and sensitive data (such as credit card information) is protected by SSL encryption when it is exchanged between your web browser and our web site. To protect any data you store on our servers we also regularly audit our system for possible vulnerabilities and attacks and we use a tier-one secured-access data center.

#### Questions or Comments

If you have questions or comments about this privacy policy, please email us at [privacy@venturebeat.com](mailto:privacy@venturebeat.com) or contact us at:

VentureBeat  
Attn: Privacy Policy Issues  
330 Townsend, Suite 134  
San Francisco, CA 94107
